UDAYKUMAR MIYATRA

Instrument Engineer



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Instrument Engineer with 3 years of experience, service & technical Support for process & Maintenance, PLC programming, Scada development.

Maintenance document record of Calibration and Service report for ISO 9001:2015.

Instrument Engineer with a positive attitude and exemplary skills.



EXPERIENCE

INSTRUMENT ENGINEER

Pranav Chemicals, Ahmedabad / Sep 2023 - Present

INSTRUMENT ENGINEER

Maize Products Ltd, Kathawada / Jan 2023 - Sep 2023

- Maintain Plant Instrument Calibration Report and Measurement
- Maintain Daily Report in logbook, Handling Shift, Team management & 5S.
- Instrument History card and Preventing Maintenance Schedule.
- Field Instrument, :-Flow Meter, Control Valve, Centrifuge, Dryer

SERVICE & INSTRUMENT ENGINEER

United instrument Services, Vadodara / Oct 2020 - Dec 2022

- Field Instrument Calibration Like Transmitter (PT, DPT, LT), Indicator, Scanner, PID, etc...
- Provide Technical Support for the maintenance, operator and troubleshooting of Process Instrument.
- Control Panel Design as per Customer requirement and take approval it from customer.
- Erection and commissioning of PMS (Power Monitoring system) in Roha DyeChem (Dahej).
- Program Developed For conveyor rejection unit for PI industries, Panoli.
- Develop and successfully commissioned, Control System withthe various analog and digital I/Os with HMI (RENU make) at IDEX India PVT LTD, Vadodara.
- Commissioning of Tank Filling System using Schneider M241plc and Citect Scada at J.K. Cement, Rajasthan.
- Developed EMS System and Successfully Commissioning at UPL-3.
- Installed GPS Clock in DCS At SRF, Dahej.
- Basic Knowledge of orifice, networking and electrical panel.
- Knowledge about reading piping and instrumentation diagram.



CONTACT

-mail·

udaymiyatra316@gmail.com

Phone:

9723994932

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/uday-miyatra-5657b5193

*

CERTIFICATS

- Industrial training, Ajanta LTD.
- PGDIA by Prolific.
- Concept of PLC by Prolific.



SOFT SKILLS

 On point communication with sound reasoning to reach common interests for project tasks or project completion.



HARD SKILLS

- PLC SCADA AutoCAD
- Field Instrument
- PID tunning
- Calibration
- HMI
- PMS/EMS



EDUCATION

M.Sc. Instrumentation & Control

Sardar Patel, Vidhyanagar
 2017 - 2019

B.Sc. / Instrumentation

Sardar Patel, Vidhyanagar
2014 - 2017



REFERENCE

Mitesh Patel

- United Instrument Services Managing Partner

Chirag Panchal

- United Instrument Services
Project Engineer